window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "C_Programming - Array_and_Pointer — Slot 1 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Array_and_Pointer — Slot 1",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C program:<pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\n\nint main(){\n    int a;\n    int arr[5] = {30,50,10};\n    int *ptr;\n    ptr = &amp;arr[0] + 1;\n    a = *ptr;\n    (*ptr)++;\n    ptr++;\n    printf(\"%d\", a + (*ptr) + arr[1]);\n    return 0;\n}\n</code></pre>\nThe output of the above program is ___________. (Answer in integer) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2025 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "111",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/460841/gate-cse-2025-set-2-question-52#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C program:<pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\n\nvoid stringcopy(char *, char *);\n\nint main(){\n    char a[30] = \"@#Hello World!\";\n    stringcopy(a, a + 2);\n    printf(\"%s\\n\", a);\n    return 0;\n}\n\nvoid stringcopy(char *s, char *t) {\n    while(*t)\n        *s++ = *t++;\n}\n</code></pre>Which ONE of the following will be the output of the program? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2025 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>@#Hello World!</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Hello World!</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ello World!</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Hello World!d!</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Hello World!d!</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/460826/gate-cse-2025-set-2-question-9#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p><pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nvoid foo(int *p, int x) {\n    *p = x;\n}\n\nint main() {\n    int *z;\n    int a = 20, b = 25;\n    z = &amp;a;\n    foo(z, b);\n    printf(\"%d\", a);\n    return 0;\n}\n</code></pre>\nThe output of the given C program is __________. (Answer in integer) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2025 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "25",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/460056/gate-cse-2025-set-1-question-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>The pseudocode of a function fun() is given below:<pre><code>\nfun(int A[0,...,n-1])\n{\n    for i=0 to n-2\n\tfor j=0 to n-i-2\n\t    if (A[j] &gt; A[j+1])\n\t\tthen swap A[j] and A[j+1]}\n}\n</code></pre>\nLet \\(A[0, \\dots, 29]\\) be an array storing 30 distinct integers in descending order. The number of swap operations that will be performed, if the function fun() is called with \\(A[0, \\dots, 29]\\) as argument, is __________. (Answer in integer) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2025 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "435",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/460057/gate-cse-2025-set-1-question-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Consider an array X that contains n positive integers. A subarray of X is defined to\nbe a sequence of array locations with consecutive indices.<br>\nThe C code snippet given below has been written to compute the length of the\nlongest subarray of X that contains at most two distinct integers. The code has two\nmissing expressions labelled (P) and (Q).<br><pre><code>\nint first=0, second=0, len1=0, len2=0, maxlen=0;\nfor (int i=0; i &lt; n; i++) {\n\t if (X[i] == first) {\n\t\tlen2++; len1++;\n\t } else if (X[i] == second) {\n\t\tlen2++;\n\t\tlen1 = (P) ;\n\t\tsecond = first;\n\t } else {\n\t\tlen2 = (Q) ;\n\t\tlen1 = 1; second = first;\n\t }\n\t if (len2 &gt; maxlen) {\n\t\tmaxlen = len2;\n\t}\n\t  first = X[i];\n}</code></pre>\nWhich one of the following options gives the CORRECT missing expressions?<br><br>\n(Hint: At the end of the i-th iteration, the value of len1 is the length of the longest\nsubarray ending with X[i] that contains all equal values, and len2 is the length\nof the longest subarray ending with X[i] that contains at most two distinct values.) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(P)   len1+1    (Q)     len2+1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(P)   1         (Q)     len1+1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(P)   1         (Q)     len2+1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(P)   len2+1    (Q)     len1+1</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>(P)   1         (Q)     len1+1</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422865/gate-cse-2024-set-2-question-32#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>What is the output of the following C program?<pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main() {\ndouble a[2]={20.0, 25.0}, *p, *q;\np = a;\nq = p + 1;\nprintf(\"%d,%d\", (int)(q - p), (int)(*q - *p));\nreturn 0;}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>4,8</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1,5</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>8,5</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1,8</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>1,5</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422871/gate-cse-2024-set-2-question-26#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C function definition.<pre><code>\nint fX(char *a){ \nchar *b = a; \nwhile(*b)\nb++;\nreturn b - a;}</code></pre>\nWhich of the following statements is/are TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The function call fX(\"abcd\") will always return a value</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Assuming a character array c is declared as char c[] = \"abcd\" in main(), the function call fX(c)will always return a value</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The code of the function will not compile</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Assuming a character pointer c is declared as char *c = \"abcd\" in main(), the function call fX(c)will always return a value</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>The function call fX(\"abcd\") will always return a value</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422874/gate-cse-2024-set-2-question-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>What is printed by the following ANSI C program?<pre><code>#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main(int argc, char *argv[])\n{\n int a[3][3][3] =\n {{1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9},\n {10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18},\n {19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27}};\nint i = 0, j = 0, k = 0; \nfor( i = 0; i &lt; 3; i++ ){\n\n     for(k = 0; k &lt; 3; k++ ) \n      printf(\"%d \", a[i][j][k]);\n printf(\" \\n\");\n}\nreturn 0;\n}\n</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1 2  3\n<br>\n10  11  12\n<br>\n19  20  21</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1 4  7<br>\n10  13  16<br>\n19  22  25</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1  2  3\n<br>\n4  5  6\n<br>\n7  8  9</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1 2  3\n<br>\n13  14  15\n<br>\n25  26  27</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>1 2  3\n<br>\n10  11  12\n<br>\n19  20  21</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371903/Gate-cse-2022-question-33#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>What is printed by the following ANSI C program?<pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main(int argc, char *argv[])\n{\nint x = 1, z[2] = {10, 11};\nint *p=NULL; p=&amp;x;\n*p=10;\np =&amp;z[1];\n*(&amp;z[0]+1)+=3;\nprintf(\"%d, %d, %d \\n\",x,z[0],z[1]); return   0;\n}\n</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1, 10, 11</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1, 10, 14</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>10, 14, 11</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>10, 10, 14</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>10, 10, 14</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371925/Gate-cse-2022-question-11#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following ANSI C program.<pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main( ) \n{\n    int arr[4][5];\n    int  i, j;\n    for (i=0; i &lt; 4; i++) \n  {\n        for (j=0; j &lt; 5; j++) \n        {\n            arr[i][j] = 10 * i + j;\n        }\n    }\n    printf(\"%d\", *(arr[1]+9));\n    return 0;\n}</code></pre>  What is the output of the above program? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>14</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>20</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>24</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>30</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>24</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357530/gate-cse-2021-set-2-question-10#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Following declaration of an array of struct, assumes size of byte, short, int and long are 1,2,3 and 4 respectively. Alignment rule stipulates that n byte field must be located at an address divisible by n, the fields in the struct are not rearranged, padding is used to ensure alignment. All elements of array should be of same size.<br><pre><code> Struct complx\n       Short s\n       Byte b\n       Long l\n       Int i\nEnd Complx\nComplx C[10]</code></pre>Assuming C is located at an address divisble by 8, what is the total size of C, in bytes? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>150</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>160</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>200</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>240</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>160</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "NOTE: This question is Excluded\nfor\nevaluation. <br><a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331318/isro2020-74\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>What is output of the following 'C' code assuming it runs on a byte addressed little endian machine?<br><pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main()\n{\n    int x;\n    char *ptr;\n    x=622,100,101;\n    printf(\"%d\",(*(char *)&amp;x)*(x%3));\n    return 0;\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>622</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>311</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>22</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>110</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>110</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331225/isro2020-62\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>What is the output of the code given below?<br><pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main()\n{\n    char name[]=\"satellites\";\n    int len;\n    int size;\n    len= strlen(name);\n    size = sizeof(name);\n    printf(\"%d\",len*size);\n    return 0;\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>100</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>110</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>40</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>44</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>110</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331463/isro2020-61\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C program.<pre><code>    #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\n    int main ()  {\n        int  a[4] [5] = {{1, 2, 3, 4, 5},\n                        {6, 7,8, 9, 10},\n                        {11, 12, 13, 14, 15},\n                        {16, 17,18, 19, 20}};\n        printf(\"%d\\n\", *(*(a+**a+2)+3));\n        return(0);\n    }</code></pre>The output of the program is _______. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "19",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/333209/gate2020-cs-22#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C program:<pre><code>\n#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint main() { \n  int a[] = {2, 4, 6, 8, 10}; \n  int i, sum = 0, *b = a + 4; \n  for (i = 0; i &lt; 5; i++ ) \n  sum = sum + (*b - i) - *(b - i); \n  printf(\"%dn\", sum); \n  return 0; \n} </code></pre>\nThe output of above C program is __________ . Note: This was Numerical Type question. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2019)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "10",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/302795/gate2019-cs-53#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
